Corporate Communications | Digital Marketing | Project Management

Dynamic content creator and project manager who understands complex concepts and effectively communicates intricate details to both internal and external stakeholders to achieve results. Applies knowledge of customer behavior and psychology to enhance client acquisition, improve user experience, and influence product evolution.

SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- New Hire Training and Development
- Client Relations
- Jira, Confluence, ZenDesk
- SEO
- Digital Marketing
- Editing
- Writing and Reporting
- Social Media Management
- Project Management
- Salesforce
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- HTML, CSS
- UX Writing

EXPERIENCE

Justworks

New York, NY

November 2021 - present

Sr. Implementation and Communications Manager — Justworks Payroll

September 2024

Responsibilities: Oversee all mass customer communications, including email campaigns, customer notifications, and in app text updates. Coordinate new feature launches by creating internal and external resources, identifying audience sectors for beta testing, and organizing customer outreaches. Collaborate with the Product Team to enhance platform features and optimize the user experience. Review existing processes to develop more streamlined and efficient standard operating procedures. Manage clients' accounts throughout onboarding.

Accomplishments:

- Built out the external and internal knowledge bases for Justworks Payroll's functionality and processes,
- Directed content design for new platform features, such as the 'Custom Pay Schedule' onboarding option,
- Managed all mass external communications, such as feature launches, product updates, and client deadlines.

Implementation Manager - Justworks Payroll

August 2023

Responsibilities: Established new workflows and processes as a founding member of the Justworks Payroll Implementation Team. Managed clients' accounts throughout onboarding, processing their first payroll, and ongoing support outreaches. Worked cross-functionally with Product, Operations, and Engineering teams to resolve bugs, implement new features, etc. Created internal resources and external resources, such as Help Center articles, one-pagers, and email communications. Trained new team members on the platform and implementation process.

Accomplishments:

- Adapted to new processes and compliance guidelines to onboard 93 of Payroll's first 300 customers,
- Executed quarterly communications campaigns regarding clients' state tax filings,
- Constructed consultative relationships with Payroll's first clients,
- Created more than 20 of Justworks Payroll's first Help Center articles,
- Collaborated with the Product Team to onboard the first Payroll client with integrated health insurance policies,

Customer Success Representative and Mentor — Justworks PEO

November 2021

Responsibilities: Used HR platforms, and understood payroll operations, health insurance, tax filings, to provide daily support to PEO clients. Managed client inquiries by researching platform errors, navigating resources and collaborating with internal teams to resolve requests. Hit expected metrics each day while supporting new team members, hosting shadow hours, and providing guidance on their customer interactions. Contributed to the Social Media Team by monitoring customer interaction on Sprout and responding accordingly.

Accomplishments:

- Quickly mastered HR tech platforms (Jira, Confluence) and went from temporary to permanent within four months.
- Promoted to proficiency within six months.
- Exceeded daily metric mark of 30 client interactions, averaging up to 85 interactions during peak seasons,
- Maintained 97% average Quality Assurance scoring of all interactions,
- Mentored five new hires who went on to become proficient in the role,
- Partnered with the Communications Team to manage social media platforms and create comms campaigns.

Erika Echternach

eechternach12@gmail.com | Minneapolis, MN | www.linkedin.com/in/erikaechternach/

WebFX

Remote

Copywriter May 2020 - November 2021

Responsibilities: Wrote engaging, SEO-focused copy to generate leads for clients from a wide variety of industries. Conducted in-depth research on the respective industry, product, and services, then adapted to the client's tone and style to produce effective B2B and B2C branded content. Fact-checking and editing my articles, as well as workshopping pieces submitted by other copywriters.

Accomplishments:

- Promoted to Associate Copywriter within a year.
- Produced 15% more copy per day than peers.
- Entrusted with copy editing for other writers.

Sea Cliff Consulting

Remote

Freelance Editor September 2021 - December 2021

Responsibilities: Assisted client with re-launching their website by curating digital content and revising existing articles to streamline the site. Researched industry-specific details to ensure copy was technically accurate and up-to-date. Corrected grammar and adjusted wording to make jargon and complex concepts more digestible for consumers.

Capital News Service

Richmond, VA

Staff Writer November 2019 - May 2020

Responsibilities: Covered the Virginia General Assembly and reported breaking news. Pitched timely and newsworthy story ideas relevant to Virginia constituents. Interviewed state politicians and produced weekly news articles. Created graphics based on local statistics, such as crime rates, to accompany stories.

East-West International Ministries

Sidoarjo, Indonesia

English Teacher May 2019 - August 2019

Responsibilities: Taught English to local Sidoarjo children and adults who had been displaced from their home country and were seeking asylum in Indonesia. Created lesson plans, and planned special events, such as Science Week, for the students. Led group lessons as well as individual tutoring sessions. Learned a working level of Bahasa Indonesia in order to communicate more effectively with my students.

City Hub

Sydney, NSW, Australia

News Writer May 2018 – July 2018

Responsibilities: Wrote a minimum of two news feature pieces each week for the City Hub newspaper. Interviewed politicians, small business owners, and local Sydneysiders for quotes. Studied Australian politics, culture, and language to ensure my articles were accurate and relevant. Attended opera performances, political launch parties, concerts, restaurant openings, and more to publish reviews. Collaborated to produce the paper's annual 'Best of Sydney' issue. Edited pieces submitted by colleagues who were not native English speakers and coached them on best practices.

EDUCATION

University of Richmond Richmond, VA

Bachelor of Arts — Journalism and Leadership Studies, Double Major

- Cumulative GPA: 3.94
- Division I Athlete Cross Country and Track & Field